<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Abhishek Saxena</title>
    <description>Hi, I&#39;m Abhishek Saxena. I&#39;m a Software Engineer, Code Geek, Singer, Guitarist and a Gamer.
</description>
    <link>http://abhisheksaxena7.bitbucket.org//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://abhisheksaxena7.bitbucket.org//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 11:55:10 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 11:55:10 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Soundcloud Covers and OC&#39;s!!</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;hi-friends&quot;&gt;Hi friends,&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Music&lt;/strong&gt; is something which calms the soul and directly soothes the mind and body together. Some like to listen to it and others who are more blessed with talents of playback, composing; make music!.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My love for music started off pretty early. I was always a choir student in my school. I remember how I used to be the only guy in the front row feeling so shy as I was surrounded by 2 girls on my right and 2 on my left. I learned playing synthesiser when I was in 2&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; standard. Now apart from singing, I had also started playing synth in the class assembly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Numerous competitions and years later I developed a taste for western music when I was introduced to one of the &lt;code&gt;cult&lt;/code&gt; band of our generation &lt;code&gt;Linkin Park&lt;/code&gt;. Then later on &lt;code&gt;EMINEM&lt;/code&gt; became my &lt;code&gt;Rap-God&lt;/code&gt;. Seeing my passion for music, my grandmother bought me my first acoustic Guitar. Now I wanted to learn &lt;strong&gt;Guitar&lt;/strong&gt;!! So there I was learning Guitar at summer classes, at the end of those 15 days I had learnt the basics of it and on the gala night of the classes I even performed with one of the most famous bands in our city &lt;code&gt;The Oceans&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well things went slow until I met one of my friend who played &lt;code&gt;Electric Guitar&lt;/code&gt;. He inspired me to learn guitar further. So I bought a shining new &lt;code&gt;ESP-F10&lt;/code&gt; and the journey continued. I joined my college band &lt;code&gt;Sarhad&lt;/code&gt; performed with them on many occassionas, played as a solo artist on separate occassions. Music still remains not a hobby but a passion and the journey continues!!. Here are some of my songs which I have recorded these past few years. I hope you like them. Feel free to comment and let me know your views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could find me on &lt;a href=&quot;http://soundcloud.com/abhisheksaxena7&quot;&gt;SoundCloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2015 14:54:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://abhisheksaxena7.bitbucket.org//music/2015/08/16/My%20tracks/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://abhisheksaxena7.bitbucket.org//music/2015/08/16/My%20tracks/</guid>
        
        
        <category>music</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Debut with Blogging!!</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;hello-fellas&quot;&gt;Hello Fellas!!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since past few weeks I’ve been really bored with the daily monotony. Waking up at 5, going to gym, swimming and then &lt;strong&gt;nothing&lt;/strong&gt;. I was simply &lt;strong&gt;procrastinating&lt;/strong&gt;. I even deactivated whatsapp/facebook to stop this. I started a few things like learning &lt;code&gt;Spanish&lt;/code&gt; and it felt good studying a totally new language, but the charisma, spark and excitement I felt while &lt;code&gt;programming&lt;/code&gt; was missing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created my last website a long time back and since then my interest in web development had also decreased, but a website for myself was long due. So one day when I stumbled onto &lt;code&gt;Jekyll&lt;/code&gt; while looking at a friend’s website created on it. I was suddenly craving to make one for myself. I started browsing about it. I had some experience using &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; but didn’t know much anything about &lt;code&gt;jekyll&lt;/code&gt; so I started googling about it, and hours and hours later this is the result in front of all of you. My own personalized Jekyll based website. Made up from scratch in less than a day :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you guys appreciate the content I’ll be posting. If you have any suggestions for this website feel free to post a comment below and let me know about the topics you’d like to read about.
&lt;br /&gt;
Cheers to the new begining!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 15:22:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://abhisheksaxena7.bitbucket.org//blog/2015/08/15/Welcome%20to%20my%20site/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://abhisheksaxena7.bitbucket.org//blog/2015/08/15/Welcome%20to%20my%20site/</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
